Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
What's on the menu? Accident or incident?
ما على القائمة؟ حادث أم حادثة؟
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
Cooking classroom?
فصل طهو دراسيّ؟
Yeah.
أجل
A teacher named Uemori Michi runs it out of her home.
تُديره معلّمة تُدعى أويموري ميتشي من منزلها
I've heard of her! She teaches French cooking, right?
أعرفها، فهي معلّمة في الطهو الفرنسيّ، صحيح؟
Yeah! Sonoko asked if I'd like to go with her this Sunday.
أجل! دعتني سونوكو لمرافقتها إذا كنتُ أريد الذهاب هذا الأحد
Thanks for the food!
شكراً على الطعام
I've always wanted to study French cuisine, so I told her I'd go!
لطالما أردتُ دراسة الطهو الفرنسيّ، فقبلتُ دعوتها
What time does it start?
ومتى يبدأ الفصل؟
It starts at 6:30 and ends at around 9:30.
يبدأ عند السادسة والنصف وينتهي عند قرابة التاسعة والنصف
9:30?
التاسعة والنصف؟
Forget it! That's too late!
!لا ينفع! هذا متأخّر كثيراً
But it's right nearby, in Haido!
!لكنّه في جادة هايدو بالقرب
That still doesn't matter!
!وإن كان بالقرب
Hey! Let's go with her, then!
لنرافقها في تلك الحالة إذاً
What?
ماذا؟
We might get to eat the teacher's yummy French food for free!
قد نستطيع أكل الطعام الفرنسيّ اللذيذ !الذي تعدّه المعلّمة بالمجّان
Yummy French food...
طعام فرنسيّ لذيذ؟
Sunday
الأحد
Something suddenly came up, so Sonoko couldn't come.
وهكذا، لم تستطع سونوكو القدوم بسبب ظرفها الطارئ
Listen, Ran. I didn't come along because I want to eat French food.
اسمعي يا ران، لم أرافقك لأنّي أريد أكل الطهو الفرنسيّ
I'm just worried about you.
بل لأنّي قلق عليك
Yes, yes. I understand.
حسناً، حسناً، فهمت
Do you really?
أفهمتِ حقّاً؟
Dad! This is it!
!هذا هو المكان يا أبي
Mori Ran-san, yes?
موري ران-سان، صحيح؟
Yes!
أجل
We were told you were coming!
أخبرتنا المعلّمة بأنّك ستأتين
Here you are!
هاك
Thank you!
شكراً
Thanks!
شكراً لك
Komiyama Yuko (24)
أنا كومياما يوكو، مساعدة المعلّمة
I'm Komiyama Yuko, the teacher's assistant.
(24) كومياما يوكو
Over there is a student, the teacher's old high school classmate,
الجالسة هناك هي تلميذة وزميلة قديمة للمعلّمة من المدرسة الثانويّة
and a boutique owner, Yashiro Kazue-san.
ومالكة متجر أزياء، ياشيرو كازوي-سان
Yashiro Kazue (52)
(ياشيرو كازوي (52
Nice to meet you.
سُررت بلقائكم
It's nice to meet you!
!سُررنا بلقائك
This is my father and Conan-kun.
هذا أبي، وكونان-كن
What an impressive classroom!
!يا للفصل الحسن
Are these the cooking counters?!
أهذه منضدات الطهو؟
Wow! What a big oven!
!يا للفرن الكبير
Ovens are vital to French cooking!
!لا غنى عن الفرن في الطهو الفرنسيّ
And we get to eat the food you make at that table?
أسنأكل الطعام الذي تصنعونه على تلك الطاولة إذاً؟
Yes.
أجل
It's Nishitani-kun.
إنّه نيشيتاني-كن
Bonsoir! Let's have another good class!
!مساء الخير"! أتمنّى درساً موفقاً لنا اليوم أيضاً"
I slept well...
نمتُ كثيراً
Let me introduce you!
!سأعرّفكما عليهم
This is Mori Ran-san, who's filling in for Sonoko-san tonight!
هذه موري ران-سان التي تشغل !مكان سونوكو-سان الليلة
And this is her father and Conan-kun.
كما والدها وكونان-كن
It's nice to meet you!
!سُررنا بلقائكم
Uemori Kaoru (25)
(أويموري كاورو (25
Oh. Well, good luck.
حسناً، بالتوفيق
Kaoru-san is the teacher's son's wife.
كاورو-سان هي زوجة ابن المعلّمة
Nishitani Hiroaki (29)
(نيشيتاني هيرواكي (29
I'm Nishitani. Nice to meet you.
أنا نيشيتاني، سُررت بلقائكم
Nishitani-san is a French chef.
نيشيتاني-سان طاهي مطعم فرنسيّ
Oh, Kaoru-san. What's with that eye patch?
كاورو-سان، ما خطب ضمادة العين هذه؟
I have a sty...
...بي شحاذ عين
Is Sonoko-san not feeling well?
أتعاني سونوكو-سان من توعّكٍ ما؟
No, apparently something urgent came up.
كلا، كان لديها ظرفٌ طارئ
It's only natural that she'd want to skip class...
لا عجب أنّها لن تحضر الفصل
Being yelled at every time...
فقد كانت تتلقّى الصراخ كلّ مرّة
You should be ready for it yourself.
يجدر بك تحضير نفسك
Kazue-san! Quit scaring her!
!كازوي-سان! كفّي عن إخافتها
Don't worry. You won't be the only one she yells at.
لا تقلقي، لن تكوني الوحيدة التي ستصرخ عليها
Okay...
حسناً
Uemori-sensei sounds really strict...
!تبدو أويموري سينسي صارمةً جدّاً
Ah, so that's why ol' Sonoko ran off and used Ran as a replacement.
فهمت، لذا افتدت سونوكو نفسها بران وهربت
Oh, Yuko-san! I'll help!
!يوكو-سان! سأساعدك
Incidentally, has Uemori-sensei gone somewhere?
بالمناسبة، أذهبت أويموري سينسي لمكانٍ ما؟
Yes, the beauty salon.
أجل، صالون التجميل
The beauty salon?
صالون التجميل؟
Beauty salon?!
!صالون التجميل؟
Her French recipe book became a best-seller,
،أصبح كتابها للطهو الفرنسيّ من الكتب الأكثر مبيعاً
and there's a party tomorrow in celebration of that.
وستُقام حفلة غداً احتفالاً بذلك
She's really something.
إنّها عجيبةٌ حقّاً
Making lots of money off of others' ideas...
تسرق أفكار الناس وتجني طنّاً من الأموال منها
One-third of the recipes in that book are hers... Yuko-san's.
...ثلث الوصفات المذكورة في الكتاب
Stop it, Kazue-san. That doesn't matter.
توقّفي رجاءً يا كازوي-سان، لا يهمّ ذلك
Oh? Why not?! Your own recipes have been stolen!
!ماذا؟ لمَ؟ فقد سُرقت وصفاتك
You came up with those original recipes
ابتكرتِ تلك الوصفات الأصليّة بينما تجتهدين
while working so hard these past five years as Michi's assistant!
!مساعدةً لميتشي في الخمسة أعوامٍ الفائتة
But she did help...
...لكنّها ساعدت
So what if she helped a little? They're clearly your recipes!
!وماذا إذا ساعدتك قليلاً؟ تبقى وصفاتك أنت
Yet, you don't complain at all. You must be crazy!
مع ذلك لا تتذمّرين البتّة، لا بدّ أنّ هناك علّةً بك
Quit it, Kazue-san!
!توقّفي يا كازوي-سان
This is between our teacher and Yuko-san! It's none of our business!
!هذا أمرٌ بين المعلّمة ويوكو-سان! لا حقّ لنا بالكلام
Oh, really?
حقّاً ذلك؟
I guess you're right.
ربما صحيح
Michi has been giving you financial assistance all this time.
فقد كانت ميتشي تقدّم لك دعماً مادياً باستمرار
So you can't say anything bad about her.
فلا تستطيع التفوّه بسوء عنها
That has nothing to do with this.
الموضوعان مختلفان
Oh? I'd love to hear how they're not related.
ماذا؟ كيف مختلفان؟ هلّا أسمعتني؟
It's--!
...ذلك
Oh, man. Things are getting weird in here...
مهلكم، الجوّ ينقلب هنا
She's back!
!رجعت المعلّمة
Welcome back, Teacher!
!مرحباً بعودتك يا معلّمة
Uemori Michi (52)
(أويموري ميتشي (52
I'm back. I'm a little late, it seems.
رجعت، يبدو أنّي تأخّرت قليلاً
You must be Mori Ran-san.
لا بدّ أنّك موري ران-سان
Yes! It's nice to meet you!
!أجل! سُررت بلقائك
I'm Ran's father, Mori--
...أنا والدها، موري
Oh, my shoulders are stiff.
يا إلهي، كتفاي متصلّبان
Nishitani-kun. If you would.
نيشيتاني-كن، من فضلك
Right.
حسناً
U-Umm, I'm M-Mori...
...ا-المعذرة، أنا مـ-موري
Here's the blouse you asked me to mend.
هذه البلوزة التي طلبتِ منّي إصلاحها
Yeah. Put it there.
حسناً، ضعيها هناك
Kaoru-san. Check my pulse.
كاورو-سان، تفقّدي نبضي
Right.
حسناً
Sheesh. Can't even say, "Thank you."
يا إلهي، دون كلمة شكر واحدة حتّى
Is she unwell?
أتعاني المعلّمة من توعّكٍ ما؟
She's just fat.
إنّها بدينةٌ وحسب
She always has her pulse checked like that after going somewhere.
تطلب تفقّد نبضها بعدما ترجع من مكان دوماً
Kaoru-san used to be a nurse.
كانت كاورو-سان ممرضة
It's a little fast, but it's fine.
إنّه سريعٌ قليلاً، لكن لا داعي للقلق
Her son is an elite businessman,
ابنها رجل أعمالٌ متفوّق
but he grew up as an only child and has a terrible mother complex.
لكنّه كان ابنها الوحيد، وربّته بحُب فلديه عقدة أمّ كبيرة
Kaoru-san has it tough, being Michi's daughter-in-law.
وضع كاورو-سان صعب بما أنّها زوجة ابنها
I heard the teacher's husband died of an illness.
سمعتُ أنّ زوج المعلّمة تُوفي من مرض
Yes.
صحيح
He was such a nice, gentle man...
كان رجلاً لطيفاً وصالحاً
That'll do. I'm going to change now.
يكفي هذا، سأغيّر ثيابي
Okay.
حسناً
I need to use the bathroom.
سأذهب لدورة المياه
I'll just go get an apron.
وسأذهب أنا لجلب مريلة
Hold on!
!مهلك
There's no smoking in here!
!التدخين ممنوع في هذه الغرفة
I'm sorry, but you'll have to smoke outside.
آسفة، لكن عليك التدخين في الخارج
Sorry.
المعذرة
Umm, where is the bathroom?
لو سمحتِ، أين دورة المياه؟
Through that door and to the left. There's one for men and women.
،اذهبي عبر ذاك الباب وانعطفي يساراً توجد واحدة للفتيان وأخرى للفتيات
Thank you.
شكراً لك
Guess I'll go, too.
سأذهب بدوري
Yuko-san. I know what I said earlier, but...
...يوكو-سان، رغم كلامي قبل قليل
Ran-san!
!ران-سان
Sorry! My mistake! You look alike!
!آسف! تبدوان متشابهتين فخلطت بينكما
Okay, let's begin.
لنبدأ إذاً
Today, we'll be making mushroom terrine and duck in orange sauce.
سنعدّ اليوم طاجن فطر وبطّ بصلصة البرتقال
Dessert will be pear clafouti.
ستكون التحلية كلافوتي إجاص
Whoa, now. You're cooking with a ring on?
مهلك، ستطهين وأنت ترتدين خاتمك؟
Even if you are good, that's not very professional...
حتّى لو كنتِ بارعة، هذا ليس احترافياً
Nishitani-san is wearing a ring, too?!
!حتّى نيشيتاني-سان يرتدي خاتماً؟
Like teacher, like student...
هذا التلميذ من تلك المعلّمة
That sounds great! Duck, huh?! I just love duck!
!يبدو هذا رائعاً! بطّ إذاً؟ أنا أحب البطّ
Yuko-san.
يوكو-سان
R-Right! I'm sorry!
!أ-أجل! آسفة
Huh? You're closing it?
ماذا؟ ستغلقينه؟
I'm sorry.
آسفة
Geez!
!يا إلهي
Oh, Dad...
...أنت يا أبي
We'll start with the mushroom terrine.
سنبدأ بصنع طاجن الفطر
I'll make some myself, so watch me and follow my example.
سأعدّه حتّى المنتصف، فراقبوني وقوموا بتقليدي
First, slice 200 grams of champignon.
نقطّع 200 غراماً من الغاريقون أوّلاً
Hey. What's champignon?
أخبرني، ما هو هذا الغاريقون؟
It means "mushroom."
إنّه فطر
Now, we sauté it in butter.
نقليه بالزبدة
Make sure to boil the moisture away.
تأكّدوا من غلي النداوة تماماً
It's starting to smell good!
!بدأت رائحته تطيب
But we won't get to eat it for a long while.
لكنّك لن تستطيع أكله لفترة
You're quite good at that!
أنتِ تعدّينه ببراعة
Thank you!
!شكراً
You're so inept. You haven't changed one bit.
أنتِ عديمة الكفاءة حقّاً، لم تتغيّري عن الماضي البتّة
What's this? Now you can't separate the white and the yolk.
ماذا؟ لا يمكنك فصل الصفار والبياض هكذا
We're only using the white.
سنستعمل البياض فقط
I'm sorry. I can only see with my right eye, so it's hard to tell...
،آسفة، أستطيع الرؤية بعيني اليمنى فحسب ...لذا يصعب عليّ الانتباه
No excuses!
!بلا أعذار
Yuko-san. I don't see the Gruyere cheese!
كما يوكو-سان، لا أرى جبنة الغرويير
Right! I'm sorry! I'll get it now!
!آسفة! سأجلبها فوراً
All three of you are hopeless!
!لا أمل منكنّ أنتنّ الثلاثة حقّاً
She's an intense teacher...
...يا لها من معلّمة حادّة الطباع
Yeah. It's no wonder Sonoko is avoiding her.
بالفعل، لا عجب أنّ سونوكو هربت
Nishitani-san is skilled, so she has nothing to say to him.
نيشيتاني-سان بارع، فلم تقل شيئاً له
I can't stand it anymore!
!لم أعد أحتمل
I'm going for a smoke!
!سأذهب للتدخين
Wait a minute. The only way outside is through the kitchen.
انتظر، الطريق الوحيد للخروج هو عبر المطبخ
I saw a back door past the bathrooms.
كان هناك باب خلفيّ عند دورة المياه وفقما أذكر
Huh? It's unlocked...
ماذا؟ إنّه غير مقفل
What a careless household...
...يا للمنزل المهمل
What happened? A blackout?
ما الذي حصل؟ انقطاع تيّار؟
Who's there?
من هناك؟
Yuko-san! Go to the electrical room and check the breaker!
يوكو-سان! اذهبي لغرفة المفاتيح !الكهربائيّة وتفقّدي القواطع
Right!
!حسناً
Say! Did you hear a sliding door open?!
أخبرني، ألم تسمع صوت فتح باب مزلاجيّ؟
A sliding door?
باب مزلاجيّ؟
Excuse me!
المعذرة
I'm sorry, but could you give me some light?
آسفة، لكنّي أحتاج إنارة
Electrical Room
غرفة المفاتيح
That's strange. Why is the switch off?
هذا غريب، لمَ المفتاح مطفأ؟
I'll turn it on.
سأفتحه
Ice...
...جليد
What's this doing here?
لمَ يوجد هنا؟
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Mister! Someone set up a trick here to cut the power!
!يا عمّ! نصب أحدهم حيلةً لقطع التيّار
What?
ماذا؟
That weight's tied to a ring.
ذاك الثقل مربوط بحلقة
They put the ring around the switch, and the weight on the ice!
!وُضعت الحلقة حول المفتاح، والثقل على الجليد
In other words, if the ice melted...
...أي
...the ring would be pulled down and turn the switch off.
ستُسحب الحلقة، وتطفئ المفتاح تلقائياً
But who set this up?
لكن من نصب هذا؟
Let's go back to the classroom! Something might've happened!
!لنرجع للفصل! ربما حصل شيءٌ ما
Alright!
!حسناً
Dad!
!أبي
What happened?!
ما الذي حصل؟
It's the teacher! She says her chest hurts and it's hard to breathe!
المعلّمة! إنّها تقول أن صدرها يؤلمها !ولا تستطيع التنفّس
Hey! Who opened the front sliding door?!
!أخبروني، من فتح الباب المزلاجيّ الأمامي؟
Nobody did.
لم يفتحه أحد
Nobody?!
!لا أحد؟
M-My back hurts...
...ظـ-ظهري يؤلمني
I felt a sharp pain in my back while the lights were out...
شعرتُ بألمٍ حادّ في ظهري ...بينما الأنوار مُطفأة
I can barely breathe...
...التنفّس صعب
Did you strain a muscle?
هل أجهدتِ عضلةً ما؟
She can barely breathe?! Could it be?!
!تعاني في التنفّس؟ أيمكن؟
Let me see!
!اسمحوا لي قليلاً
H-Hey! What are you doing?!
!ما-ما الذي تفعله؟
C-Conan-kun?!
كونان-كن؟
Just as I thought!
!كما ظننت
She was stung by a bee!
!طعنتها نحلة
A bee?
نحلة؟
See? Here!
انظر، هنا
There's a red speck here!
!توجد نقطة حمراء
It's right behind her right lung!
إنّها وراء رئتها اليمنى تماماً
Her right lung?
رئتها اليمنى؟
T-This is--!
...هـ-هذا
Ran! Call an ambulance right away! And Inspector Megure, too!
!ران! اطلبي الإسعاف فوراً !واتّصلي بالمفتّش ميغوري أيضاً
R-Right!
!حـ-حسناً
She needs to get to a hospital right away!
ستكون في خطر إذا لم !ننقلها للمشفى فوراً
But who did this?!
لكن من فعل هذا؟
No one is to step outside this classroom!
يا جماعة، لا يغادر أحدكم الفصل رجاءً
And don't touch the front door, either!
ولا تلمسوا الباب الأمامي أيضاً
What gives you the right to give us orders?!
أيّ حقّ لديك لتملي علينا الأوامر؟
Pardon my late introduction. I am Mori Kogoro, the detective.
،اعذروني على التأخّر بتقديم نفسي لكنّي موري كوغورو، مُتحرٍّ
The famous detective...
...ذاك المتحرّي الشهير
...Mori Kogoro?
موري كوغورو؟
Could you explain what's happened here?
هلّا شرحت ما حصل هنا؟
I believe someone stabbed Uemori Michi-san in the back
أظنّ أحدهم طعن أويموري ميتشي-سان في ظهرها
with something with a sharp tip, like an ice pick or an awl.
بشيءٍ حاد الرأس، مثل كسّارة ثلج أو مثقاب
Come again?!
!ماذا؟
She was stabbed...
...طُعنت
...in the back?
في ظهرها؟
Yes. There was a red speck on her back, like a bug bite.
أجل، كانت هناك نقطة حمراء على ظهرها، كما لو لسعتها حشرة
An ice pick or something similar would leave such a mark.
تترك كسّارة الثلج وما شابهها آثاراً كتلك
And, even though ice pick stab marks don't look like much,
ورغم أنّ طعنة كسّارة الثلج ،لا تبدو شيئاً كبيراً
they can often pierce lungs and other internal organs.
لكنّها قد تخترق الرئتين وأعضاء داخليّة أخرى في حالات كثيرة
So the reason her chest hurt and she couldn't breathe was because...
...سبب ألم صدرها ومعاناتها في التنفّس إذاً
She may have a hole in her lung.
لعلّ هنالك ثقباً برئتها
So, who did this?
ومن الفاعل إذاً؟
Ran and the others heard the sliding door shortly after the blackout,
سمعت ران والبقيّة صوت فتح الباب ،المزلاجيّ بعد انقطاع التيّار بقليل
so it's highly likely the perpetrator entered from outside.
فمن المرجّح أنّ الفاعل أتى من الخارج
Outside?
من الخارج؟
But that doesn't rule out an inside attacker.
لكن لا ينفي ذلك احتماليّة الهجوم الداخليّ
I see.
فهمت
I must ask that none of you leave the room.
أرجو ألّا يغادر أحدكم الغرفة
We'll check for fingerprints on the door first.
سنرفع البصمات عن الباب المزلاجيّ أوّلاً
Who was the last person to touch the door handle?
من كان آخر شخص لمس مقبض الباب؟
Nishitani-san was!
!نيشيتاني-سان
He was the last person here to arrive,
كان آخر الواصلين هنا
and when Uemori-sensei came, he opened the door from the inside!
وعندما رجعت أويموري سينسي، فتح الباب من الداخل
Then we'll need to take your fingerprints
سنحتاج لأخذ بصماتك أوّلاً
to differentiate them from the attacker's.
للتمييز بينها وبين بصمات الفاعل
Tell me about this other thing of yours.
أخبرني عن ذاك الموضوع الآخر أيضاً
Right.
حسناً
So this back door was unlocked?
كان هذا الباب الخلفيّ غير مقفل إذاً؟
Yes, Inspector.
أجل حضرة المفتّش
I believe the attacker snuck into the electrical room via the back door
وفق استنتاجي، فقد تسلّل الفاعل لغرفة المفاتيح هذه عبر الباب الخلفيّ مع بدء الفصل
and set up the ice trick.
ونصب حيلة القالب الجليديّ
The attacker then went around to the front,
ذهب بعدها للجانب الأمامي من هنا
hid in the shrubbery in the yard, and waited for the power to go out.
واختبأ في شجيرات الفناء، وانتظر انقطاع التيّار
The instant it went out, they opened the door, leapt into the classroom,
ولحظة انقطاعه، فتح الباب واندفع لغرفة الفصل
and stabbed Uemori-san and fled!
!وطعن أويموري-سان ثمّ هرب
But the classroom was pitch-dark.
لكن كانت الغرفة مُظلمة
How did the attacker find her?
كيف وجدها القاتل؟
Well, uhh...
...ذلك
She had something shiny on, or something that made her stand out.
،لعلّها كانت ترتدي شيئاً لامعاً !أو شيئاً جعلها تبرز
No.
كلا
She wasn't wearing anything like that.
لم تكن ترتدي أشياء كتلك
I don't think she was, either.
أظنّ ذلك أيضاً
Then the attacker must've used infrared goggles or something.
لا بدّ أنّ الفاعل استعمل مناظير أشعّة تحت الحمراء وما شابه إذاً
That would let them see in the dark.
يمكنك الرؤية في الظلام بها
Yes.
أجل
Are you serious? Infrared goggles aren't that easy to get ahold of.
أأنت جاد؟ لا تستطيع الحصول على مناظير الأشعّة الحمراء بسهولة
Incidentally, the old guy says it was likely an outside attacker,
بوضع ذلك جانباً، قال العمّ أنّ احتمالية ،الهجوم الخارجيّ عالية
but it's strange that there are no shoeprints left on the floor.
لكن عدم وجود آثار حذاء الفاعل على الأرض يثير الغرابة
Did the person actually take off their shoes before coming in?
هل تكبّد عناء خلع حذائه قبل الدخول؟
That's crazy!
!مستحيل
Well?
ما النتيجة؟
Right. Only Nishitani-san's fingerprints were on both door handles.
حسناً، وجدنا بصمات نيشيتاني-سان وحده على مقبضَي الباب
The attacker was probably wearing gloves,
كان الفاعل يرتدي قفّازات غالباً
and Nishitani-san touched the door last, so that's to be expected.
ونيشيتاني-سان آخر من لمس الباب، فلا عجب
Yes.
أجل
But, oddly enough, the outside handle fingerprints are fully there.
،لكنّ الغريب أنّ البصمات على المقبض الخارجي كانت مكتملة
Only the inside fingerprints are somewhat gone.
بينما بصمات المقبض الداخلي ممحوّة قليلاً
What?!
!ماذا؟
That's not right!
هذا غريب
If the attacker opened the door from the outside,
إذا فتح الفاعل الباب ،من الخارج بقفّازات
Nishitani-san's fingerprints on the outside handle should be gone!
فيُفترض أنّ بصمات نيشيتاني-سان !على المقبض الخارجيّ قد اختفت
The fact the inside fingerprints have rubbed off...
كون البصمات على المقبض ...الداخليّ هي ما مُحيت
...means the attacker opened the door from the inside!
!يعني أنّ الفاعل فتح الباب من الداخل
Huh? What are you getting at?
ماذا؟ ما الذي تلمّح له؟
The attacker didn't enter from outside!
!لم يدخل الفاعل من الخارج
Someone in the classroom opened it from the inside to deceive us!
فتح أحد المتواجدين في الفصل !الباب من الداخل لإيهامنا بذلك
They most likely used a handkerchief or something to do it!
!واستعمل منديلاً أو ما شابه لفعل ذلك غالباً
In other words, one of you four is responsible!
!أي أنّ الفاعل أحدكم الأربعة
Y-You can't be serious!
!لا-لا يمكن
It's me.
إنّه أنا
What?!
ماذا؟
All right.
حسناً
Uemori-san has just passed away due to respiratory failure
تُوفيت أويموري-سان للتوّ بسبب فشل تنفّسي
resulting from a punctured lung.
من ثقب رئويّ
That means this is now a murder case.
هذا يعني أنّ هذه القضيّة أصبحت قضيّة جريمة قتل
You killed her, Kazue-san!
!المجرم هو أنت يا كازوي-سان
Yuko-san. You held a grudge because she stole your recipes.
يوكو-سان، كنتِ حاقدةً عليها بدورك لسرقتها وصفاتك
Now I got it!
!اكتشفتُ هذه المرّة
You killed her, Kaoru-san!
!المجرم هو أنت يا كاورو-سان
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Cooking Classroom Murder Case (Part 2)."
جريمة قتل فصل الطهو الدراسيّ (الجزء الثاني)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Ring.
خاتم
Next episode you'll know who the culprit is.
!في الحلقة القادمة، أعرف هويّة المجرم
The pitcher who threw a home run at the start of the game.
!إنّه الرامي الذي تسبّبت رميته الهائجة بدورة كاملة